[Music]
hi I'm Sam and this is my life story I
was born in batong Province 1978 the
genocide in Cambodia started 1975 to
1979 my parents are from here but during
the war time we got we fled we left to
the states when I was about 11 the the
first S I stayed in 1989 was doorchester
a lot of Vietnamese Community a lot of
Cambodian so I didn't have to speak a
word of English like we was able to
communicate with them eat with them talk
to them play games with them so didn't
really feel like I was too far away from
home in college I I studyed political
science cuz again I want to my my my
dream my goal is always to want to be
able to find a way to help people then I
graduated to 2001 and my mom said there
that there's no way that she will let me
come back to Cambodia to help so but
then I I still have
uh to find a way to help people that I
started working for John hanok in
Boston I was there for about 8 years
working in
operations I got my 95 I got my house I
got my car but I was UN happppy some
something was
missing then my boss boss said they can
open manual life in Cambodia they open
you serious I end up having a a VC with
the uh CEO of Cambodia man like Cambodia
Robert Elliot he said get it on I'm here
and I'm still here going three years I I
I maybe one of the fewest people that
experienced culture shock twice when I
went to the States I could not eat lunch
I don't I don't eat burgers I hate
cheese I don't eat hot dogs like what is
this it took me 20 something years to
learn how to speak to get used to the
food and then I got here and then I go
oh kambing people all my people you know
I feel like fit in I feel like at home
am a twoo later actually I had this
conversation with Robert OT I said
Robert I think I'm an American I won my
hot dogs I miss my Burgers I wanton my
pizza I I I can't do this this rting
every single day so now I'm I'm I'm I'm
learning the people here are very nice
they very sweet so I I I do feel feel in
deep inside I do feel like I I do fit in
I believe in destiny the only thing I
know is if not from manual I Hancock I
would not have a chance to be here I
work here in man like Cambodia it's
honestly it's just very rewarding so
everything we do everything we touch I
can feel the impact every project I'm a
part of every decision that I make I can
really change that's what what I love
being
here I can see the man like Cambodia is
moving and it's moving up giving to the
back to the community opening people
with a higher bigger volume I'm very
proud to be a part of that and I will
always tell anybody that I'm a part of
that so for the Next Generation with
cambodians take the opportunity be here
and make a
difference thank you for watching
featuring Asia if you have a story to
share write to us at the email address
on your screens
[Music]
now